[
    {
        "category": "COMP SCIENCE",
        "difficulty": "Novice",
        "question": "What does Equivalence relation hold?",
        "options": [
            "Reflexivity, Symmetry and Equality",
            "Reflexivity, Symmetry and Transitivity",
            "Reflexivity, Antisymmetry and Transitivity"
        ],
        "correctOption": "B",
        "points": "1"
    },
    {
        "category": "COMP SCIENCE",
        "difficulty": "Novice",
        "question": "Explain the concept of variables in programming. How are they used, and why are they important in computer science?",
        "options": [
            "Variables are used to store constants in a program, and they are not crucial in computer science.",
            "Variables are used to store and manipulate data, making it dynamic and essential in computer science.",
            "Variables are only used in mathematical calculations and are not relevant in computer science."
        ],
        "correctOption": "B",
        "points": "1"
    },
    {
        "category": "COMP SCIENCE",
        "difficulty": "Intermediate",
        "question": "Which of the following statements about object-oriented programming (OOP) is true?",
        "options": [
            "Inheritance allows a class to inherit properties and behaviors from another class.",
            "Polymorphism is the process of converting objects into primitive data types.",
            "Encapsulation is primarily concerned with creating multiple instances of a class."
        ],
        "correctOption": "A",
        "points": "2"
    },
    {
        "category": "COMP SCIENCE",
        "difficulty": "Intermediate",
        "question": "In BDDs, if you have n variables, how many decision nodes do you have?",
        "options": [
            "n^2-1",
            "2^n-1",
            "n^2"
        ],
        "correctOption": "B",
        "points": "2"
    },
    {
        "category": "COMP SCIENCE",
        "difficulty": "Expert",
        "question": "How would you represent binary integers using <integer> and <digit> (you define it as <integer>?",
        "options": [
            "<digit> ::= <digit><integer> | <digit>\n <digit> ::= 1 | 0",
            "<integer> ::= <integer><digit> | <digit>\n <integer> ::= 0 | 1",
            "<integer> ::= <digit><integer> | <digit>\n <digit> ::= 0 | 1"
        ],
        "correctOption": "C",
        "points": "3"
    },
    {
        "category": "COMP SCIENCE",
        "difficulty": "Expert",
        "question": "In distributed systems, what is the CAP theorem?",
        "options": [
            "It describes the three essential components of a database management system.",
            "It defines the trade-offs between consistency, availability, and partition tolerance in distributed databases.",
            "It outlines the principles of network security for cloud-based applications."
        ],
        "correctOption": "B",
        "points": "3"
    },
    {
        "category": "COMP ORG",
        "difficulty": "Novice",
        "question": "What is the central processing unit (CPU) in a computer responsible for?",
        "options": [
            "Managing the computer's network connections",
            "Performing arithmetic and logic operations on data",
            "Storing files and documents"
        ],
        "correctOption": "B",
        "points": "1"
    },
    {
        "category": "COMP ORG",
        "difficulty": "Novice",
        "question": "In twoâ€™s complement, what do positive numbers have in common?",
        "options": [
            "They are negative in decimal system",
            "Most significant bit is set to 0",
            "Most significant bit is set to 1"
        ],
        "correctOption": "B",
        "points": "1"
    },
    {
        "category": "COMP ORG",
        "difficulty": "Intermediate",
        "question": "Convert 23,14 (base 10) to binary.",
        "options": [
            "10111.101",
            "1011.011",
            "10111.001"
        ],
        "correctOption": "C",
        "points": "2"
    },
    {
        "category": "COMP ORG",
        "difficulty": "Intermediate",
        "question": "In computer organization, what is the function of a control unit?",
        "options": [
            "To execute arithmetic and logic operations.",
            "To manage system memory and storage.",
            "To fetch, decode, and execute instructions stored in memory."
        ],
        "correctOption": "C",
        "points": "2"
    },
    {
        "category": "COMP ORG",
        "difficulty": "Expert",
        "question": "Which of the following is not a characteristic of Reduced Instruction Set Computing (RISC) architecture?",
        "options": [
            "Complex and lengthy instruction sets.",
            "A large number of general-purpose registers.",
            "A focus on simplicity and reduced execution time for instructions."
        ],
        "correctOption": "A",
        "points": "3"
    },
    {
        "category": "COMP ORG",
        "difficulty": "Expert",
        "question": "Convert 2B6 (hexadecimal) to ocal",
        "options": [
            "1266",
            "1366",
            "1260"
        ],
        "correctOption": "A",
        "points": "3"
    },
    {
        "category": "DISCRETE MATHS",
        "difficulty": "Novice",
        "question": "In a set, which of the following elements represents the Universal Set?",
        "options": [
            "The empty set ({})",
            "The set containing all the elements under consideration.",
            "The set with a single element."
        ],
        "correctOption": "B",
        "points": "1"
    },
    {
        "category": "DISCRETE MATHS",
        "difficulty": "Novice",
        "question": "What are the dimensions of an identity matrix? ",
        "options": [
            "n x n",
            "n^2 x n",
            "n x m"
        ],
        "correctOption": "A",
        "points": "1"
    },
    {
        "category": "DISCRETE MATHS",
        "difficulty": "Intermediate",
        "question": "In combinatorics, how many ways can you arrange the letters in the word 'COMPUTE' if no letter can be repeated in a single arrangement?",
        "options": [
            "1,260",
            "5,040",
            "10,080"
        ],
        "correctOption": "B",
        "points": "2"
    },
    {
        "category": "DISCRETE MATHS",
        "difficulty": "Intermediate",
        "question": "Find the sum of the first 7 terms of the geometric sequence 7,14,28,.. ",
        "options": [
            "767",
            "1003",
            "899"
        ],
        "correctOption": "C",
        "points": "2"
    },
    {
        "category": "DISCRETE MATHS",
        "difficulty": "Expert",
        "question": "In graph theory, what is the chromatic number of a graph?",
        "options": [
            "The maximum degree of a vertex in the graph.",
            "The minimum number of colors required to color the vertices of the graph such that no adjacent vertices have the same color.",
            "The number of edges in the graph."
        ],
        "correctOption": "B",
        "points": "3"
    },
    {
        "category": "DISCRETE MATHS",
        "difficulty": "Expert",
        "question": "What is the principle of mathematical induction used for in discrete mathematics?",
        "options": [
            "Proving theorems about prime numbers.",
            "Proving statements about an infinite sequence of natural numbers.",
            "Solving systems of linear equations."
        ],
        "correctOption": "B",
        "points": "3"
    }
]